<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>myendlesspto - My Endless PTO</title>
	<atom:link href="http://myendlesspto.me/author/myendlesspto/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://myendlesspto.me/</link>
	<description>Travel stories of a burned-out, former 9-5er</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 11:17:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Things to Know Before Visiting Phuket Big Buddha</title>
		<link>http://myendlesspto.me/5-things-to-know-before-visiting-big-buddha-phuket/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=5-things-to-know-before-visiting-big-buddha-phuket</link>
					<comments>http://myendlesspto.me/5-things-to-know-before-visiting-big-buddha-phuket/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[myendlesspto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 16:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://myendlesspto.me/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>No trip to Phuket is complete without a visit to the iconic Big Buddha. A world-famous religious and cultural symbol of Thailand, Big Buddha stands (or technically, sits) 148-feet-tall atop Nakkerd Hill in Chalong, overlooking the island of Phuket. Big Buddha is a statue of the Maravija Buddha and is accompanied by a smaller Buddha statue. The sheer sight of Big Buddha and the panoramic island views offered make it an unskippable attraction in Phuket. 1. Beware of taxi/ride scams I was caught off-guard by the taxi monopoly situation at the site where taxi drivers would crowd the entrance/exit of Big Buddha and aggressively fend off drivers they suspect are working for ride-hailing services. These taxis were asking ฿800 for a one-way ride back to Phuket Town. Unfortunately I witnessed quite a few tourists with no other alternatives agreeing to the price without second thoughts. I eventually secured a ride via inDriver again but my driver was followed by the taxi mafias and had to lie that he was there to take photos to get himself out of the situation. Just when I thought we were safe, my driver attempted to offer &#8220;side trips&#8221; (in hopes of charging extra, of course), drove in the wrong direction (which I caught very quickly as I already grew suspicious of him), then made an unannounced stop at the gas station when he asked for gas money (he claimed that he paid an entrance fee to pick me up at Big Buddha, which I knew was false as my first driver did not when he dropped us off). I was fortunate to be extra alert on all his scam attempts but I could only imagine how easy it is for many to fall victim to these scams, especially as a tourist who does not speak Thai. 2. Consider hiring a driver or joining a day tour Because transport is obviously a struggle if you do not have your own, I would highly recommend hiring a personal driver for your visit to Big Buddha. There are numerous ways you can do so: visit Klook or Tripadvisor to rent a private driver or speak to your hotel or one of the many local travel/tour agencies. I personally like upfront price transparency, cashless transactions, and customer support when needed &#8211; all of which explain my preference for online booking sites like Klook. If you want to avoid planning for your trip altogether, you can consider joining a half-day or full-day tour which includes Big Buddha as a destination. I spent ฿495 on my rides to and from Big Buddha, which could already afford me a half-day island tour of Phuket. The transport fees alone might be enough to justify joining a tour instead. 3. Check the weather Phuket receives a generous amount of rain all-year long, even when the monsoon season is over. It goes without saying that you should check the local weather before deciding when to visit Big Buddha or anywhere in Phuket. Another thing to note is that rain showers in Phuket can be extremely temperamental and sometimes scattered, so it is always a good idea to bring along an umbrella and/or raincoat in preparation of sudden downpours. 4. Cover your shoulders and legs When visiting a sacred, religious place like the Big Buddha, make sure to dress modestly and cover your shoulders and legs. Previously you were able to loan a sarong or shawl for free if you arrived without appropriate clothing but you would now have to buy one for ฿150. 5. Avoid going down the stairs leading up to the Big Buddha The main stairs leading up to the Big Buddha allows only one-way traffic. There is a security officer at the halfway-point of the stairs making sure no visitors go back down using the stairs. They have a designated exit route for visitors to get back down and it is fortunately not very far from the main stairs if you want to walk up to the statue again. I hope you find these helpful for your next visit to Phuket Big Buddha. For more travel tips and stories, please visit my homepage and stay tuned for more!</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/5-things-to-know-before-visiting-big-buddha-phuket/">5 Things to Know Before Visiting Phuket Big Buddha</a> first appeared on <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/">My Endless PTO</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img width="768" height="1024" src="http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-48" srcset="http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-768x1024.jpg 768w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-225x300.jpg 225w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-1140x1520.jpg 1140w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1887-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption>Big Buddha after a sudden afternoon rainstorm</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>No trip to Phuket is complete without a visit to the iconic Big Buddha. A world-famous religious and cultural symbol of Thailand, Big Buddha stands (or technically, sits) 148-feet-tall atop Nakkerd Hill in Chalong, overlooking the island of Phuket. Big Buddha is a statue of the Maravija Buddha and is accompanied by a smaller Buddha statue. The sheer sight of Big Buddha and the panoramic island views offered make it an unskippable attraction in Phuket.</p>



<h2><strong>1. Beware of taxi/ride scams</strong></h2>



<p>I was caught off-guard by the taxi monopoly situation at the site where taxi drivers would crowd the entrance/exit of Big Buddha and aggressively fend off drivers they suspect are working for ride-hailing services. These taxis were asking ฿800 for a one-way ride back to Phuket Town. Unfortunately I witnessed quite a few tourists with no other alternatives agreeing to the price without second thoughts. I eventually secured a ride via inDriver again but my driver was followed by the taxi mafias and had to lie that he was there to take photos to get himself out of the situation. Just when I thought we were safe, my driver attempted to offer &#8220;side trips&#8221; (in hopes of charging extra, of course), drove in the wrong direction (which I caught very quickly as I already grew suspicious of him), then made an unannounced stop at the gas station when he asked for gas money (he claimed that he paid an entrance fee to pick me up at Big Buddha, which I knew was false as my first driver did not when he dropped us off). I was fortunate to be extra alert on all his scam attempts but I could only imagine how easy it is for many to fall victim to these scams, especially as a tourist who does not speak Thai.</p>



<h2><strong>2. Consider hiring a driver or joining a day tour</strong></h2>



<p>Because transport is obviously a struggle if you do not have your own, I would highly recommend hiring a personal driver for your visit to Big Buddha. There are numerous ways you can do so: visit <a href="https://s.klook.com/c/vw078k" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Klook</a> or <a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attractions-g293920-Activities-c42-t224-Phuket.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tripadvisor</a> to rent a private driver or speak to your hotel or one of the many local travel/tour agencies. I personally like upfront price transparency, cashless transactions, and customer support when needed &#8211; all of which explain my preference for online booking sites like <a href="https://s.klook.com/c/vw078k" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Klook</a>. </p>



<p>If you want to avoid planning for your trip altogether, you can consider joining a half-day or full-day tour which includes Big Buddha as a destination. I spent ฿495 on my rides to and from Big Buddha, which could already afford me a half-day island tour of Phuket. The transport fees alone might be enough to justify joining a tour instead. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="768" height="1024" src="http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-53" srcset="http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-768x1024.jpg 768w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-225x300.jpg 225w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-1140x1520.jpg 1140w, http://myendlesspto.me/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/IMG_1892-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /><figcaption>Another storm coming when one just passed</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2><strong>3. Check the weather </strong></h2>



<p>Phuket receives a generous amount of rain all-year long, even when the monsoon season is over. It goes without saying that you should check the local weather before deciding when to visit Big Buddha or anywhere in Phuket. Another thing to note is that rain showers in Phuket can be extremely temperamental and sometimes scattered, so it is always a good idea to bring along an umbrella and/or raincoat in preparation of sudden downpours. </p>



<h2><strong>4. Cover your shoulders and legs</strong></h2>



<p>When visiting a sacred, religious place like the Big Buddha, make sure to dress modestly and cover your shoulders and legs. Previously you were able to loan a sarong or shawl for free if you arrived without appropriate clothing but you would now have to buy one for ฿150. </p>



<h2><strong>5. Avoid going down the stairs leading up to the Big Buddha</strong></h2>



<p>The main stairs leading up to the Big Buddha allows only one-way traffic. There is a security officer at the halfway-point of the stairs making sure no visitors go back down using the stairs. They have a designated exit route for visitors to get back down and it is fortunately not very far from the main stairs if you want to walk up to the statue again. </p>



<p>I hope you find these helpful for your next visit to Phuket Big Buddha. For more travel tips and stories, please visit my <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" title="homepage">homepage</a> and stay tuned for more!</p><p>The post <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/5-things-to-know-before-visiting-big-buddha-phuket/">5 Things to Know Before Visiting Phuket Big Buddha</a> first appeared on <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/">My Endless PTO</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://myendlesspto.me/5-things-to-know-before-visiting-big-buddha-phuket/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>About Me</title>
		<link>http://myendlesspto.me/hello-world/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hello-world</link>
					<comments>http://myendlesspto.me/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[myendlesspto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 19:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://myendlesspto.me/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my little slice of the internet! I&#8217;m so glad you are here and I hope you find your own inspirations and reasons to see the world like I did. A little bit about myself. I started traveling the globe as a digital nomad in 2021 when I temporarily had the opportunity to work remotely full-time. In early 2022, I got laid off in retaliation for refusing to go back to office in-person on a regular basis. I left my toxic 9-5 gladly and continued traveling the world without looking back. Since then, I&#8217;ve travelled to 9 countries, 16 cities, and counting.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/hello-world/">About Me</a> first appeared on <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/">My Endless PTO</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my little slice of the internet! I&#8217;m so glad you are here and I hope you find your own inspirations and reasons to see the world like I did. </p>



<p>A little bit about myself. I started traveling the globe as a digital nomad in 2021 when I temporarily had the opportunity to work remotely full-time. In early 2022, I got laid off in retaliation for refusing to go back to office in-person on a regular basis. I left my toxic 9-5 gladly and continued traveling the world without looking back. Since then, I&#8217;ve travelled to 9 countries, 16 cities, and counting. </p><p>The post <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/hello-world/">About Me</a> first appeared on <a href="http://myendlesspto.me/">My Endless PTO</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://myendlesspto.me/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
